<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome: on Nathan Wright</title>
    <link>https://nathanwright11.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome: on Nathan Wright</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathanwright11.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Raman-Spectroscopy Diabetes Detection</title>
      <link>https://nathanwright11.github.io/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanwright11.github.io/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Dataset took measurements from 10 healthy and 10 diabetic patients Raman spectroscopy measurements came from four locations on patient (earlobe, inner arm, thumbnail, median cubital vein) High dimensionality, each location measurement had over 3100 features Used PCA and neural network to analyze data. Best accuracy of 88% (8 test samples)   Dataset came from Kaggle submitted by user Edgar Guevara.
Relevant paper: Guevara, E., Torres-Galván, J. C., Ramírez-Elías, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Particle Detection</title>
      <link>https://nathanwright11.github.io/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanwright11.github.io/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Used Monte Carlo simulated data to find particle of unknown mass in a particle collision 7M examples in training set, 3.5M in test set Created parameterized neural network where the parameters were different possible masses Detected 1000 GeV particle with 85% accuracy without being trained on that data   Dataset came from UC Irvine&amp;rsquo;s Machine Learning Repository.
Relevent paper: Pierre Baldi, Kyle Cranmer, Taylor Faucett, Peter Sadowski, and Daniel Whiteson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine Quality</title>
      <link>https://nathanwright11.github.io/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanwright11.github.io/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Used Random Forest classification to predict quality of red &amp;amp; white wines from Vinho Verde region of Portugal Prediction based on 11 physicochemical properties (ABV, acidity, sulfates, etc.) Analyzed 1600 red &amp;amp; 4900 white wines, classes were imbalanced Achieved overall precision of 70% on red wine and 67% on white wine    Dataset came from UC Irvine&amp;rsquo;s Machine Learning Repository.
Relevant paper: P. Cortez, A. Cerdeira, F. Almeida, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://nathanwright11.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanwright11.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Check out my social media pages.
   Platform URL     Github: https://github.com/nathanwright11   LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathanwright11/   Credly: https://www.credly.com/users/nathan-wright.8242f967    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
